بِسْمِ ٱللَّهِ ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
Au nom d’Allah، le Tout Clément، le Tout Miséricordieux.
In the name of Allāh, the Entirely Merciful, the Especially Merciful.
ٱلْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ رَبِّ ٱلْعَـٰلَمِينَ
Louange à Allah، Seigneur de l’Univers.
[All] praise is [due] to Allāh, Lord of the worlds -
ٱلرَّحْمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ
Le Tout Clément، le Tout Miséricordieux.
The Entirely Merciful, the Especially Merciful,
مَـٰلِكِ يَوْمِ ٱلدِّينِ
Souverain du Jour de la Rétribution.
Sovereign of the Day of Recompense.
إِيَّاكَ نَعْبُدُ وَإِيَّاكَ نَسْتَعِينُ
C’est Toi (Seul) Que nous adorons، et c’est Toi (Seul) Dont nous cherchons l’assistance.
It is You we worship and You we ask for help.
ٱهْدِنَا ٱلصِّرَٰطَ ٱلْمُسْتَقِيمَ
Guide-nous sur la voie droite،
Guide us to the straight path -
صِرَٰطَ ٱلَّذِينَ أَنْعَمْتَ عَلَيْهِمْ غَيْرِ ٱلْمَغْضُوبِ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا ٱلضَّآلِّينَ
voie de ceux que Tu as comblés de Tes grâces، non celle des réprouvés، ni celle des égarés.
The path of those upon whom You have bestowed favor, not of those who have earned [Your] anger or of those who are astra